

Passionate and skilled Embedded Linux Developer with High Video Streaming Tech offering 8 years of relevant experience and a proven track record of success in achieving extraordinary result. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle of any embedded video related products.

Over 8 years of IT experience in Analysis, design, and Development of various embedded software development.

Capable of excelling as part of a team or individually in a fast-paced environment. Deeply knowledgeable in video codec, media format, streaming protocol, real time system, various

protocol and standard, Android Open Source Project, and IoT.

# **Richard Lee**

#### Email:

embeddedlinuxdev1210@gmail.com

#### Phone:

+1 248 690 5693

## **Skill Highlights**

- C/C++, Java, Rust, Go, Python, Shell script
- H.264, H.265, VP8, VP9
- MP4, 3GPP, MKV, AVI
- HLS, MPEG-DASH, RTSP, RTP
- TCP/UDP, HTTP, FTP, SNMP
- PCIe/Ethernet/ModBus/CAN/USB /SPI/I2C/I2S/RS232/UART
- Linux Kernel/Driver/RootFS
- Intel/ARM/MIPS/DSP Architecture
- React & Redux, Node.js, REST API
- Typescrypt/Javascript/React
- Electronic&Analog Circuit
- DevOps, CI/CD

## Languages

English - C1

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Nanyang Technological University of Singapore (2009 – 2013)

# **Experience**

**Video Engineer on Embedded Android Platform,** 12/2019 – 05/2022 **Jumio,** USA

- Developed MPEG-DASH player using dash.js
- Designed Driver, HAL, Android System Service for use in DVB-T2 player development.
- Developed RTP streaming server with low latency on Embedded Linux of TI DM8169 platform
- Analyzed & Debugged PCR accuracy in MPEG-TS stream
- Developed demodulator and tuner driver to receive DVB-T2
- Developed transcoding module which converts from any codec to H.264 codec using Hardware Accelerator

**Embedded Firmware Developer,** 08/2017 – 09/2018 **Airbyte,** USA

- Developed real time AD convert module in STM32F407
- Tested and deployed scalable and highly available OLED interface products.
- Developed motor control system using Python on raspberry-pi board
- Documented software development methodologies in technical manuals to be used by IT personnel in future projects.
- Developed DVB-T2 receive module in DVB-T2 dongle for android.

**Embedded Software Developer,** 04/2014 – 07/2016 **BTHRUST,** Singapore

- Participated in IOT (Internet of Things) development, specializing in Smart home security systems.
- Performed high-level coding in various programming languages.
- Developed WebSocket Module in Linux OS of DM8169 processor for Camera Encoder
- Designed Redundancy System for Live Streaming Encoder.
- Developed PCIe driver in Linux system for Stream Multiplexer